Guide to the Consulate General of Ireland Records AIA.044
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Consulate General of Ireland Records
1975-1998
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Archives of Irish America
AIA.044
1 Linear Feet in 2 manuscript boxes and 1 folder in shared housing
The Consulate General of Ireland in New York City is a branch of the Embassy of Ireland that provides assistance and information to Irish citizens both visiting and living in New York including passport and visa services, authentication of documents, and advice for foreign travel. This collection consists of correspondence, press releases, invitations and reports generated by the Consulate General of Ireland's New York office. Of note are Reports of the Proceedings from the New Ireland Forum (1983-1984) and the Anglo-Irish Agreement (1985) between England Northern Ireland.
Separated Materials
Issues of the Irish Voice and the Irish People were removed to the appropriate collections.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The material in this collection was donated to the Archives of Irish America by the Consulate General of Ireland, New York office. In December 2025, Marion Casey transferred a letter and form with instructions on applying for Irish citizenship; the accession number associated with this transfer is 2026.008.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Arrangement
Files are arranged alphabetically.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of correspondence, press releases, invitations and reports generated by the Consulate General of Ireland's New York office. Of note are Reports of the Proceedings from the New Ireland Forum (1983-1984) and the Anglo-Irish Agreement (1985) between England and Northern Ireland. Also of interest are invitations to various members of the New York Irish American community to events sponsored by the Consulate.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Consulate General of Ireland in New York City provides assistance and information to Irish citizens both visiting and living in New York including passport and visa services, authentication of documents, and advice for foreign travel. The Consulate is a branch of the Embassy of Ireland which is headquartered in Washington D.C.
Correspondence.; Press releases.; Irish Americans |z New York (State) |z New York |x Politics and government.; Proceedings.; Ireland. Consulate General (New York, N.Y.); New Ireland Forum; Kennedy, Edward M. (Edward Moore), 1932-2009; Moynihan, Daniel P. (Daniel Patrick), 1927-2003
- Anglo-Irish Agreement, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1969-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Finlay, Fr. James C., S.J.: Presentation, Jul 9, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- International Fund for Ireland, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Invitations, 1969-1998, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Irish Citizenship Instructions, undated (Box Shared Tamiment 209, Folder 8)
- New Ireland Forum: Papers, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- New Ireland Forum: Papers, 1984, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- New Ireland Forum: Report of Proceedings, May 1983-Oct 1983 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- New Ireland Forum: Report of Proceedings, Oct 1983 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- New Ireland Forum: Report of Proceedings, Nov 1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- New Ireland Forum: Report of Proceedings, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Passport Application Form, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Press Releases: Anglo-Irish Agreement, Nov 1985-Nov 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Press Releases: General (I), 1975-1983 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Press Releases: General (II), 1975-1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Press Releases: General (III), 1984-1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Press Releases: General (IV), 1984-1990 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Press Releases: General (V), 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Press Releases: Irish -U.S. Parliamentary Delegation, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Press Releases: New Ireland Forum and Reports, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Taoiseach visit to the U.S. Prime Minister of Ireland, Dr. Garrett Fitzgerald), Mar 1984 (Box 2, Folder 10)